Register of the Russia. Missiia (Norway) Records, 1781-1924
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1905-1924
  - Soviet Union. Includes materials on the pre- 1917 period
    - Revolution and Civil War
      - North -- Provisional Government of the Northern Province. Includes correspondence among Russian consulates in Norway
        - 1919
          - September (Folder 9)
          - October (Folder 10)
          - November (Folder 11)
          - December (Folder 12)
        - 1920 (Folder 13-17)
        - 1921 (Box 30., Folder 1-3)
      - North West (Folder 4)
      - Siberia -- Omsk (Folder 5)
      - South (Folder 6)
      - Ufa -- Provisional Russian Government (Folder 7)
    - Romanov family
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Norway (Folder 9)
      - 300th anniversary (Folder 10)
    - Russo-Japanese War Memorial, 1909 (Folder 11)
    - Voennyi flot (Folder 12)
  - Spitzbergen
    - 1906 (Folder 13)
    - 1907 (Folder 14)
    - 1908 (Folder 15)
    - 1909 (Folder 16)
    - 1910 (Folder 17)
    - 1911 (Folder 18)
    - 1912
      - Handwritten and typewritten (Folder 19)
      - Printed (Folder 20)
    - 1913 (Box 31., Folder 1)
    - 1914
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Conference (Folder 3-6)
    - 1915 (Folder 7)
    - 1916 (Folder 8)
    - 1919 (Folder 9)
  - Stampe, Mathilde (Folder 10)
  - Stolz, Daniel (Folder 11)
  - Suomalainen, Alexander (Folder 12)
  - Sweden
    - Armed forces (Box 32., Folder 1)
    - Political conditions (Folder 2)
  - Tollefsen, M. (Folder 3)
  - Tornquist, G. (Folder 4)
  - Vorob'ev, I.I. (Folder 5)
  - Waage, Thorbjorn (Folder 6)
  - White See & Baltic Co. (Folder 7)
  - World Politics
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Eastern question (Balkans) (Folder 9)
  - World War I
    - German and Austrian atrocities (Folder 10)
    - German atrocities (Folder 11)
    - German intelligence service (Folder 12)
    - Prisoners of war
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Russian (Folder 14)
    - Relief of sick and wounded -- Aleksandrovskii komitet o ranenykh (Folder 15)
- GENERAL'NOE KONSUL'STVO, CHRISTIANIA
  - Correspondence
    - Registers, incoming
      - 1817-1841 (Box 32., Folder 16)
      - 1840-1850 (Folder 17)
      - 1851-1855 (Folder 18)
      - 1881-1888 (Box 33., Folder 1)
    - Arranged alphabetically, incoming
      - Isachsen, Daniel, 1811-1816? (Folder 2)
      - Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Arendal, 1829-1834 (Folder 3)
      - Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Bergen
        - 1811-1813 (Folder 4)
        - 1817-1833 (Folder 5)
        - 1817-1833 (Box 34., Folder 1-4)
        - 1817-1833 (Box 35., Folder 1)
      - Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Flekkefjord, 1828-1839 (Folder 2)
      - Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Molde, 1817-1840 (Folder 3)
      - Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Stavanger
        - 1822-1824 (Folder 4)
        - 1834-1840 (Box 36., Folder 1)
      - Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Trondhjem, 1811-1813 (Folder 2)
      - Ministerstvo finansov. Departament vneshnei torgovli, 1817-1832. Also see chronologically arranged correspondence (Folder 3)
      - Ministerstvo inostrannykh del, 1828-1833. Also see chronologically arranged correspondence (Box 37., Folder 1)
      - Ministerstvo vnutrennikh del. Departament politsii, 1898-1909. Also see chronologically arranged correspondence (Folder 2)
    - Arranged chronologically, incoming and outgoing
      - 1781 (Folder 3)
      - 1805 (Folder 4)
      - 1808-1811 (Folder 5)
      - 1810-1817 (Box 38., Folder 1)
      - 1811 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1811-1815. (Box 128., Folder 1-6)
        Includes correspondence of Consul-General de Brunet
      - 1811-1813 (Folder 4)
      - 1812 (Folder 5-7)
      - 1813 (Folder 8-9)
      - 1814 (Box 39., Folder 1)
      - 1814-1816, re Russian ships docking in Norwegian ports (Folder 2)
      - 1815 (Folder 3-4)
      - 1815-1816 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1816 (Folder 7)
      - 1816-1817 (Folder 8)
      - 1817 (Folder 9)
      - 1817-1837, contageous diseases and quarantine, miscellaneous documents (Folder 10)
      - 1817-1822 (Box 40., Folder 1)
      - 1817-1836 (Folder 2)
      - 1817 (Folder 3)
      - 1818-1822 (Box 41., Folder 1)
      - 1819 (Folder 2)
      - 1820, register of Russian commercial shipping passing through Norwegian ports (Folder 3)
      - 1820-1824, miscellaneous shipping records (Folder 4)
      - 1821 (Folder 5)
      - 1821-1837 (Box 42., Folder 1)
      - 1822-1827 (Folder 2)
      - 1823 (Folder 3)
      - 1824 (Folder 4)
      - 1825 (Folder 5)
      - 1826 (Folder 6)
      - 1827 (Folder 7)
      - 1829 (Folder 8)
      - 1832-1833 (Folder 9)
      - 1833, "Ot Ministerstva Innostrannykh Del. O konfiskovanniakh imenii miatezhnikov po sluchaiu miatezha v TSarstve Pol'skom. S 1833 goda." (Box 43., Folder 1)
      - 1833 (Folder 2)
      - 1834-1836 (Folder 3)
      - 1836 (Folder 4)
      - 1836-1838 (Folder 5)
      - 1837 (Folder 6-7)
      - 1837-1840 (Folder 8)
      - 1838 (Box 44., Folder 1)
      - 1838-1941 (Folder 2)
      - 1839 (Folder 3)
      - 1840 (Folder 4)
      - 1840-1844 (Folder 5-7)
      - 1840-1844 (Box 45., Folder 1-2)
      - 1841 (Folder 3)
      - 1842 (Folder 4)
      - 1843 (Folder 5)
      - 1844 (Folder 6)
      - 1844-1848 (Folder 7)
      - 1845 (Folder 8)
      - 1846 (Box 46., Folder 1-2)
      - 1847 (Folder 3-4)
      - 1850 (Folder 5)
      - 1851 (Folder 6)
      - 1852 (Folder 7)
      - 1852-1858 (Folder 8)
      - 1853 (Folder 9)
      - 1854 (Folder 10)
      - 1855 (Folder 11)
      - 1856 (Box 47., Folder 1-2)
      - 1857 (Folder 3)
      - 1858 (Folder 4)
      - 1859 (Folder 5)
      - 1860 (Folder 6)
      - 1861 (Folder 7)
      - 1862 (Folder 8)
      - 1863 (Folder 9)
      - 1864
        - March-August (Folder 10)
        - August-December (Folder 11)
      - 1864-1865 (Box 48., Folder 1)
      - 1865 (Folder 2-4)
      - 1866 (Folder 5)
      - 1867 (Folder 6-7)
        Includes register of incoming correspondence, 1867-1880
      - 1868 (Folder 8)
      - 1869 (Folder 9-10)
        Includes notebook, "Registre...des personnes auxquelles il est defendu de delivrer ou viser de passeports pour un voyage en Russie..."
      - 1871
        - Incoming
          - January-August (Box 49., Folder 1)
          - August-December (Folder 2)
        - Outgoing (Folder 3)
      - 1872
        - Incoming
          - January-September (Folder 4)
          - September-October (Folder 5)
        - Report, "Otchet o poezdke v Finnmarken..." (Folder 6)
      - 1872
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Box 50., Folder 1)
          - June-December (Folder 2)
      - 1873
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Folder 3)
          - June-December (Folder 4)
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Folder 5)
          - June-December (Folder 6)
          - General (Folder 7)
      - 1874
        - Incoming
          - January-August (Box 51., Folder 1)
          - September-December (Folder 2)
        - Outgoing (Folder 3)
      - 1875
        - Incoming (Folder 4-6)
        - Outgoing
          - January-May (Folder 7)
          - May-December (Folder 8)
      - 1876
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Box 52., Folder 1)
          - July-December (Folder 2)
        - Outgoing (Folder 3)
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Folder 4)
          - July-December (Folder 5)
      - 1878
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Box 53., Folder 1)
          - July-December (Folder 2)
        - Outgoing (Folder 3)
      - 1879
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Folder 4)
          - June-December (Folder 5)
      - 1879
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Box 54., Folder 1)
          - June-December (Folder 2)
      - 1880
        - Incoming
          - January-May (Folder 3)
          - May-August (Folder 4)
          - September-December (Folder 5)
        - Outgoing (Folder 6)
      - 1881
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Box 55., Folder 1)
          - June-December (Folder 2)
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Folder 3)
          - June-December (Folder 4)
      - 1882
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Folder 5)
          - July-December (Folder 6)
      - 1882
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Box 56., Folder 1)
          - June-December (Folder 2)
      - 1883
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Folder 3)
          - June-December (Folder 4)
        - Outgoing (Folder 5)
      - 1884
        - Incoming
          - General (Box 57., Folder 1-3)
          - January-April (Folder 4)
          - May-August (Folder 5)
          - September-December (Folder 6)
        - Outgoing
          - January-May (Folder 7)
          - May-December (Folder 8)
      - 1884
        - Documents related to whaling ship "Elena". Official circulars re laws of quarantine (Box 58., Folder 1)
      - 1885
        - General (Folder 2-5)
        - Outgoing (Folder 6-8)
      - 1886
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Box 59., Folder 1)
          - July-December (Folder 2)
        - Outgoing (Folder 3)
      - 1887
        - Incoming (Folder 4)
          - January-May
      - 1887
        - Incoming
          - May-July (Box 60., Folder 1)
          - August-December (Folder 2)
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Folder 3)
          - June-December (Folder 4)
      - 1888
        - Incoming
          - January-April (Box 61., Folder 1)
          - April-September (Folder 2)
          - September-December (Folder 3)
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Folder 4)
          - June-December (Folder 5)
      - 1889
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Box 62., Folder 1)
          - July-December (Folder 2)
        - Outgoing
          - January-July (Folder 3)
          - July-December (Folder 4)
      - 1890
        - Incoming
          - January-May (Folder 5)
          - May-July (Folder 6)
          - August-December (Folder 7)
      - 1890
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Box 63., Folder 1)
          - June-December (Folder 2)
      - 1891
        - Incoming
          - January-April (Folder 3)
          - May-August (Folder 4)
        - General (Folder 5-8)
      - 1892
        - General, mostly incoming Outgoing (Box 64., Folder 1-2)
          - January-April (Folder 3)
          - April-July (Folder 4)
          - July-November (Folder 5)
      - 1893
        - Incoming (Folder 6)
        - Outgoing (Folder 7)
      - 1894 (Folder 8-11)
      - 1895
        - Incoming
          - January-March (Box 65., Folder 1)
          - March-May (Folder 2)
          - May-October (Folder 3)
          - October-November (Folder 4)
        - Outgoing
          - General (Folder 5)
          - Vestnik finansov, promyshlennosti i torgovli (Folder 6)
      - 1895-1899 (Folder 7)
      - 1896
        - Incoming (Box 66., Folder 1-5)
        - Outgoing (Folder 6)
      - 1897
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Folder 7)
          - July-December (Folder 8)
        - Outgoing (Folder 9)
      - 1897
        - General (Box 67., Folder 1-7)
        - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 8)
      - 1898 (Folder 9-10)
      - 1899 (Box 68., Folder 1)
      - 1900, includes information re Poland expedition (Folder 2-3)
      - 1901 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1902 (Folder 6-7)
      - 1903 (Folder 8-10)
      - 1904 (Box 69., Folder 1-6)
      - 1905
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Folder 7)
          - June-August (Folder 8)
      - 1905
        - Incoming
          - September-Dec. (Box 70., Folder 1-2)
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Folder 3)
          - July-December (Folder 4)
        - General (Folder 5-10)
        - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 11)
      - 1905 (Box 71., Folder 1-3)
      - 1906
        - Incoming
          - January-March (Folder 4-5)
          - April-June (Folder 6)
          - July-September (Folder 7)
          - October-Deccember (Folder 8)
        - Outgoing (Folder 9)
      - 1906
        - General (Box 72., Folder 1-3)
        - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 4)
      - 1907
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Folder 5)
          - July-December (Folder 6)
        - Outgoing (Folder 7)
        - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 8)
      - 1908
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Folder 9)
          - July-December (Folder 10)
        - Outgoing (Folder 11)
        - General (Folder 12)
        - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 13)
      - 1909
        - Incoming
          - January-June (Box 73., Folder 1)
          - July-December (Folder 2)
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Folder 3)
          - July-December (Folder 4)
        - General (Folder 5-10)
        - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 11)
        - Reports (Folder 12)
      - 1910
        - Incoming
          - Inventory (Box 74., Folder 1)
          - January-March (Folder 2)
          - April-June (Folder 3)
          - July-September (Folder 4)
          - October-December (Folder 5)
        - General (Folder 6-8)
        - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 9)
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Folder 10)
          - July-December (Folder 11)
      - 1911
        - Incoming
          - January-March (Folder 12)
          - April-June (Folder 13)
          - July-September (Folder 14)
          - October-December (Folder 15)
      - 1911
        - General (Box 75., Folder 1-2)
        - Outgoing
          - January-April (Folder 3)
          - May-August (Folder 4)
          - September-December (Folder 5)
      - 1912
        - Incoming
          - January-March (Folder 6)
          - April-June (Folder 7)
          - July-September (Folder 8)
          - October-December (Folder 9)
          - General (Folder 10-12)
        - Outgoing
          - January-March (Box 76., Folder 1)
          - April-June (Folder 2)
          - July-September (Folder 3)
          - October-December (Folder 4)
          - General (Folder 5-8)
      - 1913
        - Incoming
          - January-March (Folder 9)
          - April-June (Folder 10)
          - July-September (Folder 11)
          - October-December (Folder 12)
        - Outgoing
          - January-June (Folder 13)
          - July-December (Folder 14)
      - 1913 (Box 77., Folder 1-9)
      - 1914, includes secret correspondence (Box 78., Folder 1-10)
      - 1915
        - Incoming, includes secret correspondence
          - January-March (Box 79., Folder 1)
          - April-June (Folder 2)
          - July-September (Folder 3)
          - October-December (Folder 4)
          - General (Folder 5-15)
      - 1915
        - Incoming
          - General (Box 80., Folder 1-11)
      - 1915
        - Incoming
          - General (Box 81., Folder 1-11)
      - 1915
        - Outgoing
          - January-March (Box 82., Folder 1)
          - April-June (Folder 2)
          - July-September (Folder 3)
          - October-December (Folder 4)
          - General (Folder 5)
      - 1915-1918, stamp book (Folder 6)
      - 1916
        - Incoming
          - May (Folder 7-8)
          - June (Folder 9-11)
          - July (Folder 12-13)
          - August (Folder 14-16)
      - 1916
        - Incoming
          - September (Box 83., Folder 1-3)
          - October (Folder 4-8)
          - November (Folder 9-11)
          - December (Folder 12-15)
      - 1916
        - Incoming
          - General (Box 84., Folder 1-10)
          - Outgoing (Folder 11-13)
      - 1916-1917
        - Incoming (Box 85., Folder 1-8)
      - 1917 (Folder 9-12)
      - 1917 (Box 86., Folder 1-6)
      - 1918 (Folder 7-11)
      - 1919 (Folder 12)
      - 1919 (Box 87., Folder 1-6)
      - 1920
        - General (Folder 7-14)
        - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E. (Folder 15)
      - 1921 (Box 88., Folder 1-4)
      - 1922 (Folder 5-7)
      - 1923 (Folder 8-9)
      - 1924 (Folder 10)
      - 1925 (Folder 11)
  - Subject file
    - General
      - 1810-1815. Orders received from St. Petersburg, including instructions for establishment of Imperial Consulate in Christiansand, 1810 (Box 128., Folder 7-10)
      - 1874-1875 (Box 89., Folder 1)
      - 1875-1884 (Folder 2)
      - 1884-1890 (Folder 3)
      - 1894-1897 (Folder 4)
      - 1897-1901 (Folder 5)
      - 1908-1909 (Folder 6)
      - 1915-1921 (Folder 7)
    - Administration and management
      - General
        - Bound
          - 1898 (Box 90., Folder 1)
          - 1907 (Folder 2)
          - 1908 (Folder 3)
          - 1909-1911 (Folder 4)
          - 1912-1916 (Folder 5)
          - 1915 (Folder 6)
          - 1916 (Folder 7)
        - Unbound
          - 1908 (Box 91., Folder 1)
          - 1909 (Folder 2)
          - 1910
            - General (Folder 3)
            - Kommissiia po reorganizatsii zagranichnoi sluzhby Ministerstva inostrannykh del (Folder 4)
          - 1911 (Folder 5)
          - 1911-1912 (Folder 6)
          - 1913-1914 (Folder 7)
          - 1914 (Folder 8)
          - 1914-1915 (Folder 9)
          - 1915 (Box 92., Folder 1)
          - 1917 (Folder 2)
          - 1920 (Folder 3)
    - Alexander II -- Monument (Folder 4)
    - Andrei Pervozvannyi (Folder 5)
    - Commerce. See also Merchant marines and Russians in Russia
      - General
        - 1842 (Folder 6)
        - 1908 (Folder 7)
        - 1909-1910 (Folder 8)
        - 1914 (Folder 9)
        - 1915 (Folder 10-11)
        - 1915-1917 (Folder 12)
        - 1917 (Box 93., Folder 1)
      - Government policies during World War I (Folder 2)
      - Koran, Adam Saulovich (Folder 3)
      - Lied (Russian version Ionas Lid) (Folder 4)
      - Merchandise
        - Bread (Folder 5)
        - Cod-liver oil (Folder 6)
        - Horses (Folder 7)
        - Wool (Folder 8)
      - Sibirskoe obshchestvo promyshlennosti, parokhodstva i torgovli. See Lied
      - Speranskii, Lavr (Folder 9)
    - Consulates, vice-consulates and consular agents. See Russian consulates, vice-consulates and consular agents
    - Dumler, Georg vs. Waage, Thorbjorn (Folder 10)
    - Explorer, Russian -- North Pole
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Sedov, Gerogii IAkovlevich (Folder 12)
    - Gol'dshtein, Iosif Markovich (Box 94., Folder 1)
    - Intelligence service (Folder 2)
    - Kristiansen, E.C. Norem (Folder 3)
    - Merchant marine (mostly Russian)
      - General
        - 1902 (Folder 4)
        - 1906-1907 (Folder 5)
        - 1908-1909 (Folder 6)
        - 1909 (Folder 7)
        - 1910-1911 (Box 95., Folder 1)
        - 1911 (Folder 2)
        - 1912 (Folder 3)
        - 1912-1913 (Folder 4)
        - 1914 (Folder 5)
        - 1915 (Folder 6)
      - Accidents. See also Ships
        - General
          - 1906-1907 (Box 96., Folder 1)
          - 1907-1908 (Folder 2)
        - Ladkin, Ivan (Folder 3)
      - Seamen, Russian and Finnish -- Financial aid
        - 1898 (Folder 4)
        - 1906-1907 (Folder 5)
        - 1907-1908 (Folder 6)
        - 1909-1910 (Folder 7)
        - 1910 (Folder 8)
        - 1910-1911 (Folder 9)
        - 1912 (Box 97., Folder 1)
        - 1914 (Folder 2)
        - 1914-1915 (Folder 3)
      - Ships
        - Anhalt (Folder 4)
        - Avrora (Folder 5)
        - Bangputis. See Milda and Bangputis
        - Brat (Folder 6)
        - Glitra (Folder 7)
        - Innesni (Folder 8)
        - Ledaal (Folder 9-10)
        - Ledaal (Box 98., Folder 1)
        - Mars (Folder 2)
        - Milda and Bangputis (Folder 3)
        - Pavel SHpolianksii (Folder 4)
        - Vsevolod (Box 128., Folder 11-13)
    - Murman (Box 98., Folder 5)
    - Navies
      - General
        - 1910 (Folder 6)
        - 1911 (Folder 7)
        - 1912 (Folder 8)
      - Russian
        - 1818-1824 (Folder 9)
        - 1906-1908 (Folder 10)
        - 1908-1909 (Folder 11)
        - 1913 (Box 99., Folder 1)
        - 1913-1914 (Folder 2)
        - 1917 (Folder 3)
    - Norway
      - Educational system (Folder 4)
      - Press. Newspapers (Folder 5-9)
    - Poliarnaia zvezda (Box 100., Folder 1)
    - Russian consulates, vice-consulates, and consular agents
      - 1904 (Folder 2)
      - 1906-1907 (Folder 3)
      - 1908 (Folder 4)
      - 1909-1910 (Folder 5)
      - 1910-1911 (Folder 6)
      - 1911 (Folder 7)
      - 1911-1912 (Box 101., Folder 1)
      - 1912-1913 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1913 (Folder 4-6)
      - 1913-1914 (Folder 7)
      - 1914 (Folder 8)
      - 1914 (Box 102., Folder 1)
      - 1914-1915 (Folder 2)
      - 1915-1919 (Folder 3)
      - 1916-1917 (Folder 4)
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 5)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
    - Russians in Russia. Inquiries from private persons
      - 1906-1907 (Folder 7)
      - 1908 (Folder 8)
      - 1908-1910 (Folder 9)
      - 1910 (Folder 10)
      - 1911 (Box 103., Folder 1)
      - 1912 (Folder 2)
      - 1913-1915 (Folder 3-4)
    - Russians outside Russia
      - General
        - 1906-1907 (Folder 5)
        - 1908 (Folder 6)
        - 1909 (Folder 7)
        - 1910 (Folder 8)
        - 1911 (Folder 9)
        - 1912 (Folder 10)
        - 1913-1914 (Folder 11)
        - 1914 (Box 104., Folder 1)
        - 1915 (Folder 2)
        - 1915-1916 (Folder 3)
        - 1916 (Folder 4)
        - 1917 (Folder 5)
        - 1918 (Folder 6)
        - 1919 (Folder 7)
      - Death. See Inheritance and succession
      - Financial aid
        - 1906-1908 (Folder 8)
        - 1908-1910 (Folder 9)
        - 1910-1911 (Folder 10)
        - 1911-1914 (Box 105., Folder 1)
        - 1914 (Folder 2-4)
        - 1915 (Folder 5)
        - 1915-1916 (Folder 6)
        - 1916 (Folder 7)
        - 1916-1917
          - Bound (Folder 8)
          - Unbound (Folder 9)
        - 1917 (Box 106., Folder 1)
        - 1917-1918 (Folder 2)
        - 1918 (Folder 3)
      - Inheritance and succession. Arranged alphabetically by name of the deceased
        - General (Folder 4)
        - A-D (Folder 5)
        - E-I (Folder 6)
        - J-L (Folder 7)
        - M-P (Folder 8)
        - R-S (Box 107., Folder 1)
        - T-Z (Folder 2)
      - Military service, Compulsory (Folder 3)
      - Return to Russia. See also Financial aid (Folder 4)
    - Soviet Union
      - Political, social, and economic conditions. Report by SHuberskii, 1918
        - Correspondence (Folder 5)
        - English version. Typescript (Folder 6)
        - Russian version. Holograph (Folder 7)
      - Visas to foreigners, 1908 (Folder 8)
    - Spitzbergen (Folder 9)
    - Sxreter, Felix (Folder 10)
    - Viking (Folder 11)
- VITSE-KONSUL'STVO, BERGEN
  also see OVERSIZE FILE
  - Correspondence
    - 1910-1915, bound incoming from Kristiania (Box 108., Folder 1)
    - 1915 (Folder 2)
    - 1915-1916, general, bound (Folder 3)
    - 1916
      - General, mostly commercial (Folder 4)
      - General, mostly commercial (Box 109., Folder 1-5)
      - Sinking of Russian ship "Tuskar'" by German submarine (Folder 6)
    - 1916-1917 (Box 110., Folder 1)
    - 1917
      - Telegrams
        - Chicherin, A. (Folder 2)
        - Kropotkin, Prince (Folder 3)
      - General, mostly commercial but also related to returning military personnel from front and returning political emigres (Folder 4-16)
      - General (Box 111., Folder 1-12)
      - General (Box 112., Folder 1-18)
      - General (Box 113., Folder 1-9)
      - Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Bergen and Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Stavanger
        - Incoming (Box 114., Folder 1-4)
        - Outgoing (Folder 5-6)
      - List of sailors lost at sea, ship loss and sailor's compensation (Folder 7-9)
    - 1917-1918
      - SS"Krasnoiarsk" (Folder 10)
      - SS"Lord" (Folder 11)
      - SS"Pluton" (Folder 12)
    - 1918
      - General (Folder 13-17)
      - General (Box 115., Folder 1-9)
      - Emelianov, N., Russian Consul in Bergen, private correspondence (Folder 10)
      - Fokina-KHlebnikova concert, miscellaneous material (Folder 11)
    - 1918-1919, Russian Mission in Christiania and Russian Consulate in Bergen (Folder 12)
    - 1919
      - Incoming (Folder 13-15)
      - Incoming (Box 116., Folder 1-9)
      - Outgoing (Folder 10-12)